Furkan Shentyurk

UTC +2 +381 61 627 4096 +7937 77 003 36 bvndls@icloud.com











Personal Statement

I am an IT Specialist with a background in <u>Systems Operations and Customer Service</u> Support. Although my experience has mainly been in support, I am also knowledgeable and skilled in the duties of QA Engineers, DevOps Engineers, System Administrators, and SREs, and always open to improving and expanding my skill set.

While my primary preference is to work from home, I am also open to hybrid work arrangements or on-site roles in either Belgrade or Novi Sad.

Skills

Soft	Hard
Fast learning	Python and Bash scripting
Communication	Linux shell, git knowledge
Problem-solving	HTML, CSS, vanilla JS knowledge
Analytical thinking	S-tier knowledge of PC hardware
Attention to detail	English (B2), Turkish (B2), Russian (Native)
Conflict resolution	DBMS: MySQL, Oracle PL/SQL
Time management	Monitoring: Zabbix, Grafana, and Graylog
Technical writing skills	Tasks & Documentation: Pyrus, Confluence
Presentation, public speech experience	Containers: Docker (CLI/Rancher/Portainer)

Experience

SENIOR SUPPORT SPECIALIST, SOVCOMBANK TECHNOLOGIES; KAZAN, RUSSIA - 2021-2023

- Provided support for car insurance, credit accounting, and cost optimization systems
- Started, maintained, and presented a new project (Implementation of VR in a bank)
- Improved internal processes by enhancing and adding documentation, refining feedback forms, and working on better inter-team communication
- Assisted in content migration for two large sites during a redesign
- Maintained project communication, hosted daily meetings
- Automated processes using Python and Bash scripting:

 1. Mobile Cost Optimization data collection and processing, report generation
 2. Health Insurance website scraping metatag information from the old website and comparison against the current one
- Helped and trained 4 new employees from scratch

SYSTEMS OPERATOR AND MAINTENANCE SPECIALIST, THE DEEP VR; KAZAN, RUSSIA - 2020-2021

- Resolved a wide variety of hardware and software-related difficulties
- Set up the equipment for the opening of a new location
- Delivered customer support on how to use VR devices
- Maintained and coordinated equipment purchases
- Ensured the best experience possible

Education

Kazan National Research Technological University

Incomplete Higher Education (2022)

Secondary Professional Education (2018-2021)

Specialty - Tourism and Recreational Services

Thesis - "Application of Virtual Reality technologies for tourism development"